<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Journey in Automating the Datacenter</title>
    <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Journey in Automating the Datacenter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Chris Arceneaux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://test.arsano.ninja/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Backup for Microsoft 365 v6</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2022/03/23/veeam-vb365-restore-portal-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2022/03/23/veeam-vb365-restore-portal-scripts/</guid>
      <description>After completing my PowerShell script to upgrade Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication environments to v10, I wanted to take the next step and automate the full lifecycle process. I&amp;rsquo;ve had Ansible in my sights for a while to do this as it can natively use PowerShell.
Markus Kraus, a Veeam VanGaurd, started work along this same train of thought last year and recently updated the code to support Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication v10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Upgrade to Veeam v11</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2021/03/09/veeam-unattended-upgrade-v11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2021/03/09/veeam-unattended-upgrade-v11/</guid>
      <description>After the release of Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication v10 last year, I wrote a PowerShell script to automate the upgrade. It&amp;rsquo;s as easy as they come as it enabled one-click upgrades of Veeam environments.
With the release of v11, I wanted to continue the tradition to enable those with multiple Veeam servers, the easy button for mass upgrades to the latest version of the product. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce the release of an updated version of this script for v11!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Update for Veeam v11</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2021/03/03/veeam-ansible-collection-v11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2021/03/03/veeam-ansible-collection-v11/</guid>
      <description>Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication v11 officially launched last week! With a new version of the product that is jam-packed with features, it&amp;rsquo;s no wonder that it&amp;rsquo;s already passed 15,000 unique downloads! Even before it was released, I was already being asked the question&amp;hellip;when will the Veeam Collection for Ansible support v11?
The answer is&amp;hellip;right now! The collection now fully supports all major components of the Veeam Availablility Suite:
 Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication Veeam Backup Enterprise Manager Veeam ONE  To the credit of the Veeam development team, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much I had to do on my end for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring API-only Features of First Class Disks</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/10/02/vmware-codeconnect-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/10/02/vmware-codeconnect-2020/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting at VMware CodeConnect on what might be the best kept secret of vSphere&amp;hellip;First Class Disks! If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are or you&amp;rsquo;d like information on capabilities and use cases, I recommend you tune in!
If anyone has any follow-up questions after the presentation, please feel free to reach out to me via Twitter or VMware Code Slack.
UPDATE:
  Here are the slides from my presentation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Ansible Setup</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/09/18/simple-ansible-setup-with-cygwin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/09/18/simple-ansible-setup-with-cygwin/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This solution should only be used in non-production environments as a method to get familiar with Ansible. For production use, I recommend installing Ansible on a dedicated Linux server.
An automated deployment tool is a must have for any IT environment. In my lab, that&amp;rsquo;s Ansible. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Ansible in my lab to automate VM deployment/destruction, adding SSH keys for remote access to my servers, joining/leaving AD domain, and monitoring the newly deployed VMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Ansible Collection</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/04/27/veeam-ansible-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/04/27/veeam-ansible-collection/</guid>
      <description>After completing my PowerShell script to upgrade Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication environments to v10, I wanted to take the next step and automate the full lifecycle process. I&amp;rsquo;ve had Ansible in my sights for a while to do this as it can natively use PowerShell.
Markus Kraus, a Veeam VanGaurd, started work along this same train of thought last year and recently updated the code to support Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication v10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Plugin for vCD w/ SSO</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/02/13/veeam-plugin-for-vcd-with-sso/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/02/13/veeam-plugin-for-vcd-with-sso/</guid>
      <description>With the release of Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication version 10 around the corner, it&amp;rsquo;s only fitting that we get some added goodness with a new version of the Veeam Plugin for vCloud Director. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that a new version of the plugin is available today!
New features of the plugin include:
 Single Sign-On (SSO) capability Support for Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication version 10 Support for VMware vCloud Director 10  Documentation for deployment &amp;amp; configuration of this plugin can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Look: Veeam Plugin for vCD </title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2019/09/27/introduction-veeam-plugin-for-vcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2019/09/27/introduction-veeam-plugin-for-vcd/</guid>
      <description>Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication version 9.5 released the vCloud Director (vCD) Self Service Portal that leverages Enterprise Manager and allows vCD Tenants to fully administer backups for their vCD workloads. Upon release, Veeam made consumption of this Self Service Portal as easy as possible as it leverages vCD authentication for tenants so they don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage two sets of credentials. Even so, it was still a separate portal independent of vCD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to CI/CD with Python</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2019/06/22/introduction-to-cicd-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2019/06/22/introduction-to-cicd-with-python/</guid>
      <description>   Useful Links  GitLab CI  GitLab CI Sample Code Test and deploy a Python application with GitLab CI/CD Using GitLab CI/CD with a GitHub repository GitLab CI Documentation   Travis CI  Travis CI Sample Code Travis CI DPL - can be used with GitLab CI as well! Travis CI Documentation     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitLab CI Artifact Expiration</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2019/05/09/automate-gitlab-artifact-deletion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2019/05/09/automate-gitlab-artifact-deletion/</guid>
      <description>Note: If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with GitLab CI, I highly recommend you try it out on GitLab.com for free.
A few months ago, the disk space on my on-prem GitLab instance began to fill up. Fortunately for me, my monitoring reported the issue before it became a major problem. My first thought was, why is this happening? I knew that I had provisioned more than enough space and there should be no reason it was almost full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating GitHub Pages Deployment</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2018/07/21/automating-github-pages-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2018/07/21/automating-github-pages-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Following the instructions for this post will enable you to use Travis-CI to deploy a Hugo-based website to GitHub Pages.
When I set out to build the website for my blog, I knew I wanted to have the ability to dynamically generate my website as well as to be able to change the theme (appearance) of the website very easily. While researching the methods to accomplish this, two tools seemed to pop up the most:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Testing &amp; Deployment of your Website</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2018/07/15/automate-website-with-travis-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2018/07/15/automate-website-with-travis-ci/</guid>
      <description>As websites go, mine is definitely in its infancy. This past week, I brought my website online by following a couple blog posts of some fellow colleagues (Thom Greene &amp;amp; Mike Tabor). The help they provided was invaluable as I was able to register a domain and get a website going in a short period of time.
After following their instructions, I immediately knew what I wanted to do to add to their instructions&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying vSphere Automation with vRealize Orchestrator</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2018/07/10/indy-vmug-usercon-2018-preso/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2018/07/10/indy-vmug-usercon-2018-preso/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to presenting at the UserCon today. I&amp;rsquo;m especially excited as vRealize Orchestrator (vRO) is a tool that I think a lot of companies could leverage to start their automation journey. If anyone has any follow-up questions after the presentation, please feel free to reach out to me via Twitter or Email.
As promised, you can download the slides from my presentation here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
