<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>one on A Journey in Automating the Datacenter</title>
    <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/tags/one/</link>
    <description>Recent content in one on A Journey in Automating the Datacenter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Chris Arceneaux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://test.arsano.ninja/tags/one/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Update for Veeam v11</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2021/03/03/veeam-ansible-collection-v11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2021/03/03/veeam-ansible-collection-v11/</guid>
      <description>Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication v11 officially launched last week! With a new version of the product that is jam-packed with features, it&amp;rsquo;s no wonder that it&amp;rsquo;s already passed 15,000 unique downloads! Even before it was released, I was already being asked the question&amp;hellip;when will the Veeam Collection for Ansible support v11?
The answer is&amp;hellip;right now! The collection now fully supports all major components of the Veeam Availablility Suite:
 Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication Veeam Backup Enterprise Manager Veeam ONE  To the credit of the Veeam development team, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much I had to do on my end for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veeam Ansible Collection</title>
      <link>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/04/27/veeam-ansible-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.arsano.ninja/2020/04/27/veeam-ansible-collection/</guid>
      <description>After completing my PowerShell script to upgrade Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication environments to v10, I wanted to take the next step and automate the full lifecycle process. I&amp;rsquo;ve had Ansible in my sights for a while to do this as it can natively use PowerShell.
Markus Kraus, a Veeam VanGaurd, started work along this same train of thought last year and recently updated the code to support Veeam Backup &amp;amp; Replication v10.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
